<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel><title>BloggEher</title><link>http://eher.github.io/index.html</link>
<description>Pieces of stuff that should be simple</description><language>en</language>
<lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 17:21:07 +0100</lastBuildDate>
<pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 17:21:07 +0100</pubDate>
<atom:link href="http://eher.github.io/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<item><title>
010PHP Composer the right way
</title><description><![CDATA[

<h1>010PHP</h1>

<p>010PHP is an user group for PHP developers living in, around and within travelling distance of Rotterdam.
On this last meetup Rafael Dohms presented his updated "Composer the Right Way" talk at Zicht Online.</p>

<p>Meetup: <a href="https://www.meetup.com/010PHP/">https://www.meetup.com/010PHP/</a></p>

<h1>Composer the right way</h1>

<p><a href="http://www.twitter.com/rdohms">Rafael Dohms</a></p>

<p>Composer has triggered a renaissance in the PHP community, it has changed the way we deal with other people’s code and it has changed the way we share our code.
We are all slowly moving to using Composer, from Wordpress to Joomla and Drupal and frameworks in between.
But many of us mistreat composer, follow outdated practices or simply lack a few tricks. In this session i’ll get you the low down on how to use composer the right way.</p>

<p>Slides: <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/rdohms/composer-the-right-way-phpugmrn">http://www.slideshare.net/rdohms/composer-the-right-way-phpugmrn</a></p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_meetup.html'>meetup</a>, <a href='tag_php.html'>php</a>, <a href='tag_010php.html'>010php</a></p>


<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href='http://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=http://eher.github.io/010php-composer-the-right-way.html&text=&lt;Type your comment here but please leave the URL so that other people can follow the comments&gt;&via=EHER'>Comments? Tweet</a> 
<a href='https://twitter.com/search?q=http://eher.github.io/010php-composer-the-right-way.html'><span id='count-16188'></span></a>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description><link>http://eher.github.io/010php-composer-the-right-way.html</link>
<guid>http://eher.github.io/./010php-composer-the-right-way.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Eher</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 17:02:24 +0100</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Familie
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>I'm starting to learn Dutch online from the very basic.</p>

<p>The website used is <a href="https://oefenen.nl/">Oefenen</a>. It means practice as far I understod.</p>

<p>So let's practice!</p>

<p>New words:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/de+baby">de baby</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/de+broer">de broer</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/de+familie">de familie</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/de+fles">de fles</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/de+luier">de luier</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/de+melk">de melk</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/de+moeder">de moeder</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/de+oma">de oma</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/de+opa">de opa</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/de+vader">de vader</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/de+zus">de zus</a></li>
</ul>

<p>Prepositions:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/in">in</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/uit">uit</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/op">op</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/onder">onder</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/naast">naast</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/achter">achter</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/voor">voor</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/tussen">tussen</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/over">over</a></li>
</ul>

<p>Review:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/de+bril">de bril</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/de+regen">de regen</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/het+huis">het huis</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/de+stoel">de stoel</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/de+jas">de jas</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/de+zon">de zon</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/de+wolk">de wolk</a></li>
</ul>

<p>Verbs:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/drinkt">drinkt</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/- groeit">groeit</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/huilt">huilt</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/lacht">lacht</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/maakt">maakt</a> / <a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/schoon">schoon</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/roept">roept</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/vindt">vindt</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/plast">plast</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/poept">poept</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/blij">blij</a></li>
</ul>

<p>Adjectives</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/verdrietig">verdrietig</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/groot">groot</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/klein">klein</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/leeg">leeg</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/vol">vol</a></li>
</ul>

<p>Questions</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/waar">waar</a></li>
<li><a href="https://translate.google.com/#nl/en/wie">wie</a></li>
</ul>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_dutch.html'>dutch</a></p>


<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href='http://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=http://eher.github.io/familie.html&text=&lt;Type your comment here but please leave the URL so that other people can follow the comments&gt;&via=EHER'>Comments? Tweet</a> 
<a href='https://twitter.com/search?q=http://eher.github.io/familie.html'><span id='count-19607'></span></a>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description><link>http://eher.github.io/familie.html</link>
<guid>http://eher.github.io/./familie.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Eher</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 00:31:01 +0100</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
DOMCODE Conference 2016
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>DomCode is a non-profit event based in Utrecht, The Netherlands. Two tracks of local and international speakers covering modern development, hosted in a friendly environment.</p>

<p>I attended to DomCode 2016 and here is my track.</p>

<h1>My track</h1>

<p>Here is the list of talks that I was attending to on the conference.</p>

<h2>Here be dragons! What it's really like to slay a monolith</h2>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/greydnls">Grahan Daniels</a></p>

<p>The prospect of transitioning from a legacy monolithic application towards a group of purpose built services sounds like a dream. In reality, it's most often an epic journey wrought with trials and tribulations.</p>

<p>In this talk you will learn how one of the fastest growing new media companies shifted from a half decade old Kohana application onto a platform comprised of micro services. We'll cover how to treat your APIs like first class citizens, the thought process behind architecting a stable publishing platform, and all of the lessons we learned along the way.</p>

<h2>Exeperience building apps with react native</h2>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/adrian_philipp">Adrian Philipp</a></p>

<p>React Native is all about combining great user experience on native platforms with the developer experience of React on the web. Since it’s start 1.5 years ago, React Native continuously enjoys a tremendous traction. In 2015 React got popular, I believe 2017 will be the year of React Native. I followed the development since the start and now built several React Native apps. During my talk I like to introduce the library, show useful tooling and give practical advice for building React Native apps.</p>

<h2>Oops! OOPS's not what i thought</h2>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/anjanavakil">Anjana Vakil</a></p>

<p>In this talk we'll go on a historical and philosophical journey deep into the heart of object-oriented programming (OOP). Come along with me as I have my world shaken by the discovery that objects and classes are not the most important concepts in OOP: messages and late binding are. Join me as we try to peek inside the heads of Alan Kay and the other founders of the paradigm as they were developing early object-oriented languages like Smalltalk, only to discover that those "old" ideas seem strikingly relevant today. We may even feel our jaws drop as we realize that OOP and functional programming are not as different as we may have thought, and that the first object-oriented language was not created in the 60's or 70's but much, much earlier…</p>

<p>What awaits us at the end of this journey? At worst, we'll experience a brief crisis of faith in everything we ever thought we knew about programming. (A support group will meet after the conference.) At best, we'll shift the way we view this near-ubiquitous but oft-misunderstood programming paradigm, and walk away with new insights for how we architect and understand our code.</p>

<h2>Distributed disarray</h2>

<p>Laurens Duijvesteijn</p>

<p>Can you build a skyscraper in a swamp? With a solid foundation, you might.</p>

<p>In this talk we'll cover some of the ridiculous things you're going to have to put up with if you want to execute your application on multiple computers. Highlights include the laws of physics and Murphy, "random" numbers, timezones plus all the fun that comes with them, and the network.</p>

<h2>How do kids program in the wild?</h2>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/felienne">Felienne Hermans</a></p>

<p>Scratch is an amazingly popular programming language for kids, with 14 million public programs available in their online repository. But, what do kids do in their programs? Are their programs simple or complex? Do they apply programming concepts or do they just play with the blocks? Do kids develop good programming habits? Are there common code patterns?</p>

<p>To answer those questions, we scraped the Scratch repository, retrieved 250,000 projects and performed source code analysis on them.</p>

<h2>How to effectively grow a development team</h2>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/jeroenvdgulik">Jeroen vd Gulik</a></p>

<p>Developers come in all forms and sizes but putting them together doesn't automatically transform them into a team. One of the keys to creating a successful team of developers in my opinion is a great developer culture. In this talk I will try to explain why developer culture is so important and share how we grew a developer culture for one of the biggest airports in Europe.</p>

<h2>Ethics &amp; human rights in a digital society</h2>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/ncilla">Ancilla van de Leest</a></p>

<p>In an environment with endless technical possibilities and need for convenience, what safeguards do we have to protect ourselves from commercial exploitation? What can we expect from our politicians? Does an individual citizen hold any responsibility for our mutual future and that of coming generations? What accountability do companies hold? Answers to these question, and more insights from Ancilla.</p>

<h1>More about the conference</h1>

<p>You can find more information on <a href="http://conference.domcode.org/">DOMCODE conference website</a>.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_conference.html'>conference</a></p>


<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href='http://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=http://eher.github.io/domcode-conference-2016.html&text=&lt;Type your comment here but please leave the URL so that other people can follow the comments&gt;&via=EHER'>Comments? Tweet</a> 
<a href='https://twitter.com/search?q=http://eher.github.io/domcode-conference-2016.html'><span id='count-1066'></span></a>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description><link>http://eher.github.io/domcode-conference-2016.html</link>
<guid>http://eher.github.io/./domcode-conference-2016.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Eher</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 00:26:55 +0100</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Bulgaria PHP Conference 2016
</title><description><![CDATA[

<h1>Open Keynote</h1>

<h2>I'm Just Here for the ElePHPants</h2>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/jmikola">Jeremy Mikola</a></p>

<p>There's so much more to experience as a PHP developer than filling the lines between some php tags. From plush elephants to game shows to camping and cruises, Jeremy will celebrate $n wonderful experiences in and around the PHP community that have built friendships lasting long after folks have moved on to other programming languages, countries, or careers.</p>

<h1>Day 1</h1>

<h2>Rewriting 15-Year-Old Code</h2>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/afilina">Anna Filina</a></p>

<p>Did you ever have to maintain a 15year-old application? Dead code and tables everywhere, static methods, database queries in between HTML tags and some pages still in PHP3. Learn how to automate legacy testing, how to seamlessly jump between the old and new parts, and how to overcome other challenges that arise from dealing with legacy.</p>

<h2>Integrating React.js into a PHP application</h2>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/andrewrota">Andrew Rota</a></p>

<p>React.js has taken the web development world by storm, and for good reason: React offers a declarative, component-oriented approach to building highly-scalable web UIs. But how can we take advantage of a JavaScript library like React in our server-side PHP applications</p>

<h2>Climbing the Abstract Syntax Tree</h2>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/asgrim">James Titcumb</a></p>

<p>The new Abstract Syntax Tree (AST) in PHP 7 means the way our PHP code is being executed has changed. Understanding this new fundamental compilation step is key to understanding how our code is being run.</p>

<h2>Scaling PHP</h2>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/dustinwhittle">Dustin Whittle</a></p>

<p>PHP is used by the likes of Facebook, Yahoo!, Zynga, Tumblr, Etsy, and Wikipedia. How do the largest internet companies scale PHP to meet their demand?</p>

<h2>Continuous WordPress, live is all good</h2>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/DragonBe">Michelangelo van Dam</a></p>

<p>WordPress is probably the most-used blogging framework on the internet, with millions of people publishing multiple articles daily and a very active community building extra functionality through plugins and themes, making WordPress the best tool for small businesses to get started with their online identity. But this popularity comes with a price: it becomes target to spammers and even worse: hackers.</p>

<h2>Jenkins vs Circle vs Travis</h2>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/msvrtan">Miro Svrtan</a></p>

<p>Jenkins, CircleCI and Travis CI are 3 most popular in PHP world. Main point of the talk is what they can do, how they do it and what are the main or subtle differences between them.</p>

<h2>Lightning Talks</h2>

<h1>Day 2</h1>

<h2>Dockerize your unit tests for faster feedback</h2>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/DragonBe">Michelangelo van Dam</a></p>

<p>WordPress is probably the most-used blogging framework on the internet, with millions of people publishing multiple articles daily and a very active community building extra functionality through plugins and themes, making WordPress the best tool for small businesses to get started with their online identity. But this popularity comes with a price: it becomes target to spammers and even worse: hackers.</p>

<p>In this session I will explain how you can harness your WordPress setup and use automated tools to keep your WordPress site (or sites) protected and up-to-date, especially when you can not use the automated update features WordPress has build-in. Stop worrying about failing plugins and keep your WordPress application up-to-date in a continuous, automated, secure way.</p>

<h2>Asynchronous Programming Fundamentals</h2>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/ieatkillerbees">Samantha Quiñones</a></p>

<p>Asynchronous programming is an increasingly important and common topic in the modern world of application development. The potential performance benefits for some applications are truly astronomical. Combining elements of message passing, and functional programming, the asynchronous model can be intimidating for developers who have worked mostly with object-oriented and procedural code. We’ll explore the fundamental concepts behind asynchronous programming and how they are used in real-world PHP packages like Guzzle, in the Hack language, and in the ReactPHP environment and walk through constructing a simple asynchronous server.</p>

<h2>How I learned to stop worrying and love Regular Expressions</h2>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/seldaek">Jordi Boggiano</a></p>

<p>This session will cover Regular Expressions from the basics to the darkest corners of this arcane art.</p>

<p>Regular Expressions at the core come in handy to achieve validation and text manipulation tasks. In the day to day life of a developer, becoming comfortable with them opens up many more use cases.</p>

<p>As one of the tortured souls that actually enjoys writing – and reading – regexes, Jordi will share his passion so that you too can see there is no reason to worry.</p>

<h2>Paradoxes and theorems every developer should know</h2>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/jaytaph">Joshua Thijssen</a></p>

<p>What do german tanks, your birthday and the speed of light have to do with our daily development work? It turns out, quite a lot!</p>

<p>During this presentation, I will explain a series of mathematical theorems and paradoxes that we encounter every day during development, but we often fail to recognize. By using these theorems, we can create better code, find more secure and efficient solutions to our problems, and it even helps you out communicating with clients and project owners.</p>

<h2>Exploiting the Brain for Fun &amp; Profit</h2>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/sketchings">Alena Holligan</a></p>

<p>Sure, you could improve yourself or promote your project the normal way, with hard work and years of slow, incremental progress. Or you could use some of the brain’s built-in cheat codes to level up on your way to success.</p>

<p>Along with learning, our brains are plagued by a raft of bugs and unwanted features that we have been unable to remove. Use these “features” to your advantage to teach, learn and persuade. Join us in a tour of some of the most amusing bugs and exploits that allow you to play with the interface between our brains and the world.</p>

<h2>Bernard, the Tactician: Background processing using message queues and the command pattern</h2>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/sagikazarmark">Mark Sagi-Kazar</a></p>

<p>Background processes are natural parts of computer science. In OSes there are daemons and services, in applications there is multi-threading, etc. This topic is becoming more and more popular in web-applications as well. In my talk, I will show what background processes are and why we should use them. I will guide the audience from a general view to an infrastructure model using message queues for background data processing and command pattern to make it nice and easy.</p>

<h2>Drinking Beer with a Raspberry Pi and PHP</h2>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/AndrewCarterUK">Andrew Carter</a></p>

<p>Always been interested in the Raspberry Pi but never known what you could do with it? Got a Raspberry Pi at home that you played with for 5 minutes before you got bored? This talk is for you.
We will be making a journey into the world of programming with sensors and other electrical components. The concepts introduced will not be specific to any programming language, but we will use PHP throughout to keep it simple. The demonstration will show how you could use a Raspberry Pi to spice up a home bar.
By the end of this talk, you will have acquired the skills to get started on your own hobby electronics projects! Maybe these skills will one day be handy introducing friends and family to the adventures of programming.</p>

<h1>Closing Keynote</h1>

<h2>Groupies, Roadies, Rockstars</h2>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/calevans">Cal Evans</a></p>

<p>Contribute to Open Source!</p>

<p>Everyone tells you that you need to. What if you don't want to run an Open Source project? What if you just need something to work? What if you jsut want to use Open Source, can you still make a contribution? Of course you can!</p>

<p>In this talk we will look at three broad groupings of roles that you can play in any Open Source project. Take a look around, find your role and your project and make a difference.</p>

<h1>More information</h1>

<ul>
<li>Site: <a href="http://www.bgphp.org/">http://www.bgphp.org/</a></li>
<li>Joindin: <a href="https://joind.in/event/bulgaria-php-2016">https://joind.in/event/bulgaria-php-2016</a></li>
</ul>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_php.html'>php</a>, <a href='tag_conference.html'>conference</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href='http://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=http://eher.github.io/bulgaria-php-conference-2016.html&text=&lt;Type your comment here but please leave the URL so that other people can follow the comments&gt;&via=EHER'>Comments? Tweet</a> 
<a href='https://twitter.com/search?q=http://eher.github.io/bulgaria-php-conference-2016.html'><span id='count-505'></span></a>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description><link>http://eher.github.io/bulgaria-php-conference-2016.html</link>
<guid>http://eher.github.io/./bulgaria-php-conference-2016.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Eher</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 00:18:11 +0100</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
My first post
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>This is my first post.</p>

<p>I'll try to use this blog to keep track of what I am doing.</p>

<p>The idea is to have something really simple to update and keep.</p>

<p>So I'll start using <a href="https://github.com/cfenollosa/bashblog">BashBlog</a> to generate the blog (in static files) using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markdown">Markdown</a>.</p>

<p>And nothing more confortable for a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_developer">web developer</a> than use <a href="https://help.github.com/articles/what-is-github-pages/">Github Pages</a> as hosting.</p>

<p>Lets see how much can I share here.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_hello.html'>hello</a>, <a href='tag_world.html'>world</a></p>


<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href='http://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=http://eher.github.io/my-first-post.html&text=&lt;Type your comment here but please leave the URL so that other people can follow the comments&gt;&via=EHER'>Comments? Tweet</a> 
<a href='https://twitter.com/search?q=http://eher.github.io/my-first-post.html'><span id='count-20347'></span></a>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description><link>http://eher.github.io/my-first-post.html</link>
<guid>http://eher.github.io/./my-first-post.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Eher</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 23:55:56 +0100</pubDate></item>
</channel></rss>
